<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<add><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/077AA8B161D64AC35E302045ADFD7DD78DDA49F9</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Aran Men carrying a Canvas Currach</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Three men are holding a currach aloft on the seashore. Four more currachs, as well as more people, are visible in the background. Currachs are wooden framed boats covered in tanned leather. They are propelled by oars and are extremely light and fast. Until the middle of the twentieth century they would have been the main form of transport for the population of the Aran Islands, where this photograph appears to have been taken.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/0A332E5736B5E62E8BF384D042922ABCFA96DD22</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">'Young Firbolgs' Aranmore</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Large group of children, both boys and girls, mostly facing camera. They are standing in front of a cottage whose partially white-washed gable is visible. Many of the girls are wearing white pinafores. Some of the boys are wearing traditional Aran kintted clothing. Welch's use of the word Firbolgs" in the caption possibly refers to the legendery motif that the Aran islands was the last bastion of the Firbolgs a small dark race of people subsequently defeated by the Tuatha de Danann in Irish myth."</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/0C4F85B58C764E0B266661DD00386AEE492ABB5B</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Cyclopean Masonry and Window of Saint MacDara’s Oratory, Roundstone</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">A view taken from inside St. MacDara's oratory. The sea is visible through the window in the gable which has been constructed of cut stone.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/14690EA703EE20FE667F8DE0FE337BB357A4E424</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Dog's Bay, Roundstone</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">The curved expanse of beach at Dog's Bay, Roundstone, is visible. There are rocky hill slopes in the background on which are dotted some white-washed cottages. One person is standing on the beach gazing out to sea. There are sand dunes in the foreground.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/15055EC59E4D225BE0152BE3C96C2F72D1CE2EAF</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Mountain Cabin, Cashel</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">The photograph shows a whitewashed thatched cabin with a door and two windows. The small garden in front is surrounded by a dry-stone wall. A woman wearing a shawl and an apron is standing in front of the cottage looking at the camera. A dog sits on a rock on the left of the photograph. Welch's caption identifes the location as Cashel and it is possibly Cashel Hill that is visible in the background.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/1B3B90335ED0465C4FCBFFF468CED105EA2D491D</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Bog cabin, Benlettery</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Six people are standing or sitting outside the entrance to a poorly constructed thatched cabin. The walls appear to be of dry stone construction and planks are used to weigh down the thatch. The girls in the photograph are barefoot but wearing white aprons despite the squalor of their surroundings.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/2DC25A9DF99C0C81BDFA6EEED3E88D5FD603A45B</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">L. Shindillagh and the Maam Turc Mountains</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of lake and mountain scenery. A portion of the shoreline, on which some trees are growing, juts out into the water from the left. The mountain in the background appears to be the lower slopes of Corcog.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/3D87FBC39BAD4BB1B533730094C580C3CD6D46BF</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Killeany Holy well station and Young Natives, Aranmore</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Five children are visible on either side of a stone opening. A stone pillar inscribed with a cross is visible beside them. The girl standing is wearing a print dress with a check shawl over her shoulders. A rocky field is visible in the background. Welch's caption identifies this as Killeany Holy Well. His reference to the children as young natives" possibly represents an imperial mindset."</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/58B52DE933088C91787FCCDEF4ABF72F254BA038</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Cashel Mountain from O’Loghlin’s Hotel</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of mountain rising in the background from lakeshore.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/5BCCBF3D7A4889A770FE06A6E1D00083738C768A</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Connemara Wool Spinning</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">A woman working a spinning wheel stands outside a partially white washing thatched cabin. A man wearing a cap and knitted scarf stands in the doorway. A basket and a shovel are on the ground close to the spinning wheel. Wool spinning was seen as one of the few possible profitable occupations in Connemara where sheep could be reared on the mountains.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/6584B060669B08B0E678289EF2195230C7BE52A0</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Benbreen '12 Bens' showing Mt. Saluscs and the results of the 'frost hammer'</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View depicting steep sloping rocky mountain terrain. Welch's first love was natural history and this is evident by the caption where he wishes to draw the viewer's attention to the effect of glaciation on the rock face.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/81982AE0FFC056C89C570C148B5C897C96B5AEE2</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Temple-na-neeve, Inchangoill, Oughterard</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">A substantial arch within a stone building is visible. A young man leans against the right hand wall underneath the arch giving an indication of the scale of the wall and the arch. There is a window in the centre of the wall underneath which is a stone slab, possibly an altar. Substantial ivy growth can be seen on the upper part of the building. Welch identifies the site as Temple na Neeve on Inchangoill Island in Lough Corrib. The photograph is probably one of the earliest photographic representations of the early medieval churches still visible on the island.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/C5A20F812D5A29EF28B5FE5FD72E88A897312E97</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kylemore Lake and Castle</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Distant view of Kylemore Castle with mountain rising to the right of the photograph</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/D7C393CAFB9D91EF034A0F36C024C1014C1C70D4</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kylemore Church</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of the gothic style church at Kylemore, Connemara. The church was built by the then owner of the Kylemore estate, Mitchell Henry, between 1877-1881, as a memorial to his wife Margaret, who had died while travelling in Egypt.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/E53381EFBA228E9B52B7B1785111A2B15A8B910C</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Roundstone</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of Roundstone village facing east. Most of the buildings are substantial two-storey houses which are still visible on Roundstone's Main Street today.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/E82D0392E4AF58A0307B429512EF52648EAC4F2E</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Crags of Ben na Sidura</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of two mountain climbers on steep rocky slope. Welch informs us this is Ben an Saighduir. Tradition suggests it is so called because a member of the Army Ordnance Corps was killed here during map surveying work for the first edition of the Ordnance Survey map in the 1830s.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/ED85EDCBC5BAD952DC4443918649F2F00B6E2B01</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Vale of Inagh and (Maam) Turk Range</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of cabin with cultivated field in foreground and body of water to the rear. A mountain rises steeply in the background.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/F39D0A437A224EF1E39009E4BDBACFDECF29D1B3</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">St. Nicholas’, Galway</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">A view of the interior of St. Nicholas' church showing five arches supported by pillars. Three windows are visible with another partially visible. A stone baptismal font is in the foreground. There are wooden pews. The floor is stone with iron heating grills inset. St. Nicholas' dates from the early fourteenth century as the oldest tomb in the church has been assigned that date. It was extended in the sixteenth century and has remained a place of worship up to the present.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/F9A07F693D61D3B62F353EBFE2C0D34F59AFB262</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kylemore Pass and Diamond Mt.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">View of lake and dramatic pass between two mountains. A road threads its way along the lake shore on the right.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15406/FB1675F466639783C2138F155F074CFFA4D5FE46</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Gleninagh and the '12 Bens' range from Lisoughter Hill</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">At least three cabins, of differing quality, are visible. The building in the foreground has a thatched roof and a single window and door. In the distance is a more substantial white-washed cottage with several windows and doors. The roof of another cottage is visble close to the water just seen at the foot of the mountain. This is Knocknahillion, part of the Twelve Bens range, with very distinct markings made by the retreating ice.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/023CB96DD57D08A518ACE77D51BEB70FF558F2E0</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kitchen Maid with the Supper at Emmaus</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/028AA5892B409B3C724F3D24D35F455BD4607C0E</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Saint Romold Taking Leave of his Parents</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/04D3186FFA85A91C828694B3A446329E9525B046</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Landscape with the Baptism of Christ in the River Jordan</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/0D61DC08352969EE50CAA73B9D71511BE76F1F69</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Bust of Cardinal Guido Bentivoglio (1577-1644)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/124CCF769A1DFA28C7AD34B46C4E9E69CE40E64A</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Group of Cavalry in the Snow: Moreau and Dessoles before Hohenlinden</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/192819259B63A637B5CE5BEB01AD976361427408</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Juno Confiding Io to the Care of Argus</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/1B92445C26341F5E24CF71D5BA170801D15CE286</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Martyrdom of Saint James the Major</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/20343E66E18EFC605D4DBB23E91924D43CCDDFF9</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Birds with Urn in a Landscape</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/234295D835D0DD98DD58328A1B6CB8E192E577FA</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Portrait of Count Johann II, Count of Montfort and Rothenfels</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/27B60B6184A25F31BF055B3B840257F97A025715</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Portrait of William, 4th Viscount Molyneux of Maryborough (c.1655-1717)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/28097463A002829C40C447EBBBA6B6A6AFCFC560</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Portrait of Sir John and Lady Clerk of Penicuik</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/2BC3203A0EA74D81D5931753126EF0421C098567</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Harvesters at Rest</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/33662EBF9CC9FE6EC6394F88DC066B027C4518A9</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Portrait of Jeronimus Tonneman and his Son Jeronimus (The Dilettanti)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/35CE4C7A92A3FA7E76B3768E75BD6610A13CD899</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Double Portrait of Bishop Robert Clayton (1695-1758) and his Wife Katherine (née Donnellan) (d.1766)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/38A3396CF9722FA81762C26E98D49224029F3F42</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Two Men Singing</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/3D49780473D9DFBD59C3C5755CEBEDB152AE5F8F</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Still Life: Two Rabbits, a Grey Partridge, Game Bag and a Powder Flask</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/3EC9342EFD35E4EA6749BE0B63A03493DF8C2CCB</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Christ in the Synagogue at Nazareth</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/3FCB61256D6CCDC7E6DE6DDE75CA15FAE31B284C</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Brazilian Landscape</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/415954D32DD6BE984F1D9623A483031E77718036</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Wooded Landscape: the Path on the Dyke</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/44AC3CAC5F14CD8E5B4415D27B46757A337E3246</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Boats on the River Lee below Tivoli, County Cork</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/457251D8081D3DF2E7941092A90CB6FFD18F933C</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Sleeping Shepherdess</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/4B2FC99F8A32217751B4C6DEC56E01CE766A5A0C</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Custom House</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/4F72BF8E88D31F714B6714C8E0672217DEF7808D</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Meuse at Dordrecht</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/5EFCD0DCE242AB7715B36F927814AE6B3E2773CA</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Saint John the Baptist in the Wilderness</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/61F17415A8062A9C9E9C8FC4936F8BE1F1626F12</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Assumption of the Virgin with Saints Jerome and Francis</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/63AFBE4D8595BD9DCF5ABA20B11259658BACD633</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Annunciation</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/6446524F0DC578529BB9827A1899A7CD11746D8C</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">The Temptation of Saint Anthony</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/64DFFAE54D508A44C6AA34E384CF7C558A1E4C49</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Landscape</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/6594D123E1A43C88181FC19A10BDEB3EE02D538F</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Woman Seen from the Back</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/15407/69FA5FE1B123661EBAD7B43AFA4CEA8F2A383941</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Portrait of a Spanish Noblewoman</field></doc></add>