<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<add><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/0DFBAA262EB5CB8C98197688FBDBEF170AF065D3</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Gilliard, P. Nikolai II:n ja hänen perheensä traagillinen kohtalo / Pierre Gilliard. - Porvoo: Werner Södeström Osakeytiö, 1924.- 284 s.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Жильяр, П. Трагическая судьба Николая II и его семьи - Порвоо: Вернер Седерстрем ОА, 1924.- 284 с.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/2D4F913FE2A185F55A47EE96311A8BD7E7BBD82A</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Ruuth, Y. O. Karjalan kysymys : vuosina, 1917 - 1920 eli katsaus karjalan-kysymyksen poliittiseen luonteeseen / Y. O. Ruuth. – Jyväskylä : K. J. Gummerus Osakeyhtiö, 1921. - 64 s. ; 21 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Руут, Ю. О. Карельский вопрос: 1917-1920, или Рассмотрение политического характера карельского вопроса / Ю. О. Руут - Ювяскюля : АО К. Й. Гуммерус, 1921. - 64 с. ; 21 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/3401682EAF35F57ADA7B2B58AD562EAADC9781B3</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Letonmäki, L. Piirteitä Suomen ja Karjalan Historiasta : valtion oppineitten neuvoston tieteellis-pedagogisen jaoston oppikirjaksi hyväksymä / kirjoittanut L. Letonmäki. - Moskova : SSR:n Kansojen Keskuskustannusliike, 1925. - 124 s. ; 23 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Летонмяки, Л. Очерки об истории Финляндии и Карелии: утверждено в качестве учебного пособия научно-педагогической секцией Государственного ученого совета / сост. Летонмяки Л. - Центральное издательство народов СССР, 1925. - 124 с. ; 23 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/5556399668C112FDD977F38DEA38F426090C2DC6</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Itkonen, T. I. Suomensukuiset kansat : 154 kuvaa ja suomalais-ugrilaisten kansojen asuma-alojen kartta / esyttanyt T. I. Itkonen. - Helsingissä : Tietosanakirja-Osakeyhtiö, 1921. - 288 s. : kuv., kartat ; 20 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Итконен, Т. И. Родственные финнам народы : 154 картинки и карта районов проживания финно-угорских народов / сост. Т. И. Итконен. - Хельсинки : АО «Энциклопедия», 1921. - 288 с. : ил., карты ; 20 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/570A414471DDDF5FA4FA4C2A3FE4286273314BFD</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kalevala / [kuv. ja pain. ohjannut Akseli Gallen-Kallela; kieliasun valvojana toim. Jalo Kalima]. - Porvoo: Werner Söderström Osakeyhtiö, 1922. - 729 s.: kuv.; 30 cm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Калевала / [сост. и ил. Аксели Галлен-Каллела; ред. Йало Калима]. – Порвоо: Вернер Седерстрем ОА, 1922. - 729 с.: ил.; 30 cм.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/60FCA23BC64F906E5221362A2E937145644E1607</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Saarimaa, E. A. Kielen ja tyylin alalta : Kirjoitelmia / E. A. Saarimaa. - Porvoossa : Werner Söderström Osakeyhtiö, 1925. - 213 s. ; 21 sm. - (Sivistys ja tiede ; 46).</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Сааримаа, Е. А. Из области языка и стиля : Очерки / Е. А. Сааримаа. - Порвоо : Вернер Сёдестрём АО, 1925. - 213 с. ; 21 см. - (Образование и наука ; 46).</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/6FD9037BB7C6D13CA5201A4D072D54B0CBC0FEF0</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Pälsi, S. Karjalan talviteillä : 81 kuvaa / Sakari Pälsi. - Helsinki : Otava, 1922. - 234, [1] s. : kuv. ; 21 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Пялси, С. На зимних дорогах Карелии : 81 иллюстрация / Сакари Пялси. - Хельсинки : Отава, 1922. - 234, [1] с. : ил. ; 21 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/A237C05C0A443243C09080DE17942E4A3C7D347D</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Morosov, S. Tie jäiden läpi : katsaus pohjoisen meritien valtaamisen historiaan / S. Morosov ; suom. Sirkka Mäkelin. - Petroskoi : Kirja, 1935. - 94, [2] s. ; 20 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Морозов, С. Путь сквозь льды: очерк об истории освоения Северных морских путей / С. Морозов; пер. на фин. Сиркка Мякелин. - Петрозаводск : Кирья, 1935. - 94, [2] с. ; 20 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/AD859036897CA0D599339453DBEFF05D401A4362</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Karjalan Kirja : [2 osa] / Paavo Ahavan [et al.] ; toim. I. Harkonen. - Porvoossa : Werner Söderström Osakeyhtiö, 1910. - 283, 547 c., [1] л. к. : ил. ; 26 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Карельская книга: [2 части] / Пааво Ахава ; ред. И. Хяркёнен. - Порвоо : Вернер Сёдестрём АО, 1910. - 283, 547 c., [1] л. к. : ил. ; 26 см. - Каждый том имеет отд. тит. л. - Авт. являются также: Й. Р. Аспелин, Х. Басильер, Ю. Бломстедт-Оёйнен.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/E21C2ECDDD29B1B9A657CC8CEF0DD6D31B8138C4</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Nansen, F. Pohjan pimeillä perillä : norjalainen napaseuturetki, 1893 - 1896, Jälimmäinen osa / Fridtjof Nansen ; suom. Teuvo Pakkala. - Helsinki : Otava, 1897. - 306 s. : kuv. ; 23 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Нансен, Ф. На темной стороне Севера: норвежская полярная экспедиция, 1893 - 1896, Последняя часть / Фритьоф Нансен ; пер. на фин. Теуво Паккала. - Хельсинки : Отава, 1897. - 306 с. : ил. ; 23 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/ECB7A8CA2C9CBC1C1B3C5E0862B229342AC7EDAD</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Härkönen, I. Runolaulajia : vanhan runon viimeinen miespolvi itäsellä suomenäärellä / Iivo Härkönen. - Helsingissä : Otava, 1926. - 159 s. : kuv. ; 19 sm.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Хяркёнен, И. Рунопевцы: последнее поколение исполнителей старых рун на востоке Финляндии / Ииво Хяркёнен. - Хельсинки : Отава, 1926. - 159 с. : ил. ; 19 см.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2023804/0733CBD2546591CA4F46F4B99E072596D9881602</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Voionmaa, V. Suomen karjalaisen heimon historia / kirjoittanut Vaino Voionmaa. - Helsinki : Kansanvalistusseura, 1915. - 543 s. ; 22 sm. - Kirjal.: s. 517-532. - Hakem.: s. 533-543.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Войонмаа, В. История карельского народа Финляндии / Вайно Войонмаа. - Хельсинки : Народное Просветительское Общество, 1915. - 543 с. ; 22 см. – Список лит.: с. 517-532. – Указ. алф.: с. 533-543.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Repository/Location: The National Library of Republic of Karelia Petrozavodsk, Republic of Karelia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Content/View Resource: jpeg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095232574</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kalevala</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tartalom ◊ ELSŐ ÉNËK ◊ Kezdődik az énëk... A világ terëmtése; Väinämöinen születése ◊ MÁSODIK ÉNËK ◊ A föld bevetése. Nehézségëk a tölggyel és az árpával ◊ HARMADIK ÉNËK ◊ Joukahainen. A lapp és a finn táltos vetélkëdése. ◊ NËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Aino tragédiája. Halála és siratása. ◊ ÖTÖDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen mëgtalálja, majd végleg elveszti Ainót s vele boldogságát. ◊ HATODIK ÉNËK ◊ Joukahainen bosszúja ◊ HETEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen Pohjolában. Pohjola úrnője ígéretët kap a Szampóra. ◊ NYOLCADIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen mëgpillantja Észak szép lëányát. Hevül érte s póruljár. ◊ KILENCEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen gyógyítása ráolvasással és bűvös gyógyírral. A vas születése. Varázsigék a vérzés elállítására. ◊ TIZEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Szampó készül Pohjolának. ◊ TIZËNËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen lëányt rabol ◊ TIZËNKETTEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Kyllikki mëgszegi ígéretét. Lemminkäinen hadba indul Észak ellen. ◊ TIZËNHARMADIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen Hiisi szarvasát űzi ◊ TIZËNNËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen mégis elfogja a szarvast, sőt Hiisi lovát is. A vadász imája az erdő isteneihëz. ◊ TIZËNÖTÖDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen anyja életre kelti holt fiát. Varázsversëk zúzott és vágott sebëkre, csonttörésre. ◊ TIZËNHATODIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen hajót épít. Varázsigékért lëszáll az Alvilágba. ◊ TIZËNHETEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen varázsigéket csikar ki "Világerőséből". Gyógyító ráolvasások belső kórság ellen. ◊ TIZËNNYOLCADIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen és Ilmarinen vërsënyt indul lëánykérőbe Pohjolába ◊ TIZËNKILENCEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Ilmarinen mëgállja a próbákat, s elnyeri Észak szép lëányát ◊ HUSZADIK ÉNËK ◊ Előkészületëk Pohjola lakodalmára. Az óriástulok mëgütése. A sör születése. ◊ HUSZONËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lakodalom Pohjolában ◊ HUSZONKETTEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lakodalom Pohjolában (folyt.). A mënyasszony búcsúztatása, ríkatása, vigasztalása ◊ HUSZONHARMADIK ÉNËK ◊ Lakodalom Pohjolában (3. rész) Intelmek az új mënyecske számára. Elrëttentő példa: a mëny sorsa idegënben ◊ HUSZONNËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lakodalom Pohjolában (4.) A fiatal férj oktatása. A mënyasszony búcsúja. ◊ HUSZONÖTÖDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lakodalom Kalevalában. Az ifjú pár fogadása a vőlegény házában. Väinämöinen a násznép dicséretét zëngi. ◊ HUSZONHATODIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen Pohja ellen indul, bosszúból, mert nëm hívták mëg a lakodalomba. ◊ HUSZONHETEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen lëgyőzi és mëgöli Pohjola urát ◊ HUSZONNYOLCADIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen bujdosni kényszërül. Anyjától kér tanácsot. ◊ HUSZONKILENCEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen vidám bujdosása ◊ HARMINCADIK ÉNËK ◊ Lemminkäinen második sikertelen hadjárata. Fagy és szëmverés elleni varázsversëk. ◊ HARMINCËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo gyermëkkora ◊ HARMINCKETTEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo pásztorkodása. Varázsigék a legelni küldött nyáj védelmére. ◊ HARMINCHARMADIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo vérës bosszút áll gazdasszonya gonoszságáért. ◊ HARMINCNËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo mëgtalálja a szüleit. Az árva panaszkodása. ◊ HARMINCÖTÖDIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo otthon is hasznavëhetetlen. Tragikus találkozása húgával. ◊ HARMINCHATODIK ÉNËK ◊ Kullervo bosszúhadjárata és halála. ◊ HARMINCHETEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Ilmarinen arany asszonyt kovácsol magának. ◊ HARMINCNYOLCADIK ÉNËK ◊ Ilmarinen másik feleségért mëgy Pohjolába. ◊ HARMINCKILENCEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Hadjárat Pohjolába, a Szampó mëgszërzésére. ◊ NEGYVENEDIK ÉNËK ◊ A kantele születése. A hajós imája. ◊ NEGYVENËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen dalol. ◊ NEGYVENKETTEDIK ÉNËK ◊ A Szampó elrablása. ◊ NEGYVENHARMADIK ÉNËK ◊ Csata a Szampóért. A csodamalom pusztulása. ◊ NEGYVENNËGYEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Väinämöinen új kantëléje. ◊ NEGYVENÖTÖDIK ÉNËK ◊ Pohjola banyája betegségëkkel rontja Kaleva fiait. Szülés-segítő és gyógyító ráolvasások. ◊ NEGYVENHATODIK ÉNËK ◊ Pohjola banyája medvét küld Kalevala ellen. A medve elejtése, a medvetor mëgünneplése. ◊ NEGYVENHETEDIK ÉNËK ◊ A nap, a hold és a tűz elrablása. Az égből hullott tűzfióka. ◊ NEGYVENNYOLCADIK ÉNËK ◊ A tűz visszaszërzése a tűznyelő hal hasából. A lën és a hálófonás meséje. Varázsigék égési sebëkre. ◊ NEGYVENKILENCEDIK ÉNËK ◊ A nap és a hold visszaszërzése Pohjolából. ◊ ÖTVENEDIK ÉNËK ◊ Marjatta szűzen szüli Karjala új királyát. Väinämöinen búcsúja. A dalnok zárószavai.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Ismertető A Svédországban élő Szente Imre arra vállalkozott, hogy a finn hőskölteményt az eredeti ritmusában, időmértékes verselésben fordítja le, s munkája értékét növeli a régies zárt ë betűk használata a szövegben. A fordító páratlanul gazdag, vidám nyelvezetű szöveggel ajándékozza meg a kötet olvasóit.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92033/BibliographicResource_3000053583973</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Ei-jumalainen komedia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">dramat polski</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Przedm. Eino Kalima.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200143/BibliographicResource_2000069316731</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kalevala</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kalevala ..</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Illustrations: Illustrations</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Edition: 3</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">3. painos.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Ed. by E. Lönnrot.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095234054</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Folia Uralica Debreceniensia 16.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Debreceni Egyetem Finnugor Nyelvtudományi Tanszékének kiadványai</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Frick, Maria: Suomi-viro-kaksikieliset yhdyssanat ◊ Hasala, Kasperi: Inkeriek - a feledésbe merült finn kisebbség ◊ Kelemen Ivett: Az -š korrelatív képző funkciói az északi lappban ◊ Keresztes László: A finnugor népek irodalmi nyelvének kérdései az újabb bibliafordítások tükrében ◊ Onyina, Szofja: Az interferencia megnyilvánulása a hanti-orosz kétnyelvűségben ◊ B. Székely Gábor: Reguly Antal kéziratos térképvázlatai és térképe (filológiai vizsgálatok) ◊ Tóth Anikó Nikolett: A lapp égtájnevek kialakulásának kérdéséhez ◊ Zaicz Gábor: A mordvinisztika másfélszáz éve Magyarországon I. ◊ Ismertetések</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200143/BibliographicResource_2000069324784</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Palaeontologie Suedrusslands</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Illustrations: Plates</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200143/BibliographicResource_2000069318237</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kanteletar</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Edition: 2</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">2. painos.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">3</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085992721</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Ruotsinsuomalaisen kirjailijan motivaatio, identiteetti ja lukutottumukset</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Sverigefinska författares motivation, identitet och läsvanor</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;In my study of Sweden-Finnish authors’ motivation, identity and reading habits I have investigated why the authors often lose their motivation to writing, why they do not have any interest in who ultimately reads their work, and what they read themselves. I ask if this could be due to their background, education or identity. Another question I asked was how they maintain their native language in an alien environment. In the group of reference there was eleven authors born between the years 1920-1947, who immigrated to Sweden between the years 1950-1984. Previous studies of the immigration of Finns to Sweden have shown that the immigrants’ first years often were traumatic and in essence a negative experience, but my study shows that within the reference group, the experiences were not as negative. The choice has been to stay in Sweden, but not to become ‘Swedish’. They see themselves not as immigrants, but as Sweden-Finns or Finns. Their native language was valued as very important but every person also spoke Swedish. There are studies that show that one can lose motivation i.e. to writing if one does not attain recognition or encouragement. This affects also one’s identity. Sweden-Finnish literature has often been disparaged by critics, which have had negative consequences on Sweden-Finnish literature as a whole. Despite difficulties in fostering their native tongue, despite negative critique and recognition, Sweden-Finnish authors write about what is meaningful to themselves. With their biographies they have proven their presence in Sweden and they have had an impact on Swedish society. Even though their books are not always praised by critics, and few buy them, they are always a welcome gift to their own grand-children.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I studien om sverigefinska författares motivation, identitet och läsvanor har min huvudfråga varit varför författares motivation för skrivandet har börjat sina. Jag har försökt ta reda på deras motiv; varför och till vem de skriver, vad de läser själva och om deras bakgrund och utbildning har något med skrivandet att göra. Hittills har forskningen i det här ämnet varit obefintlig.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I min referensgrupp ingår elva författare födda 1920-1947 som har flyttat till Sverige 1950-1984. De hade flyttat några gånger inom Finland eller bott utomlands före flyttningen till Sverige. En del har bott sedan dess i samma stad, några flyttat på grund av arbete. De har flyttat till Sverige av olika anledningar såsom familjeskäl, äventyrslust eller bättre arbete. Familjeskäl kan ha varit giftermål, skilsmässa eller barnens arbetssituation. Alla hade olika yrken bakom sig, en är fortvarande i arbetslivet. Alla hade yrkesutbildning; om de inte hade skaffat den redan i Finland så hade de studerat och vidareutbildat sig i Sverige. Ingen tillhör arbetarklassen eller har några författare i släkten. Alla har högre utbildning än sina föräldrar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jag har jämfört mitt resultat med tidigare studier om finsk invandring till Sverige. De gjordes för ca 30-40 år sedan. Då var huvudfrågorna finnarnas bakgrund och anpassning i det nya landet och man intervjuade huvudsakligen industriarbetare eller forskade i invandrarlitteratur. I min studie använder jag inte ordet invandrare utan sverigefinsk, litteratur som jag forskar i kallar jag inte till invandrarlitteratur utan sverigefinsk litteratur. Jag låter min referensgrupp vara anonym, men Pynnönen (&lt;em&gt;Siirtolaisuuden vanavedessä&lt;/em&gt;, 1991) presenterar personer och återger deras brev. Tiden är annorlunda nu och svaren som jag har fått är andra än förut fast vissa skribenter som har svarat i Pynnönens undersökning är samma skribenter som tillhör i min referensgrupp. Författare ser inte sina första år i Sverige som lika traumatiska och negativa idag som tidigare studier har visat. Ingen tänker flytta tillbaka till Finland, man har valt att stanna kvar i Sverige, men inte bli svensk för det. De känner sig inte som invandrare utan sverigefinnar eller finnar. Modersmålet upplevs som mycket viktigt men alla talar även svenska. De försökte läsa allt vad de kunde på finska men att anskaffa finsk litteratur var svårt i Sverige. Man var spetiska sverigefinsk litteratur förut men nu läste alla det. Mest lästa författare var nu som förut Väinö Linna och Kalle Päätalo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Det finns forskning som visar att man förlorar sin motivation t.ex. för skrivandet om man inte får erkännande och uppskattning. Det påverkar också ens identitet. Sverigefinsk litteratur har blivit nedvärderad av okunniga kritiker som har nästan lyckats kväva skrivandet. Sverigefinska författare är amatörer men har jämförts med Finlands främsta författare. Man har inte tagit hänsyn till böckernas innehåll utan kritiserat enbart språket. Sverigefinskan har utvecklats, fått nya ord som kommer från svensk miljö och det svenska samhället, som är främmande i Finland men det har inte kritiker tänkt på. Sverigefinska författare som har svårt att få tag i modern finsk litteratur, inte kan få tag i finska dagstidningar och bor i en annan språkmiljö har omöjligt att bevara och skriva finska språket lika bra som författare som lever och arbetar i Finland. Erkännande för sina böcker är avgörande inte bara för författares motivation utan också identitet. Man drömmer inte längre om att bli berömd författare men ändå fortsätter man sitt författarskap. Att publicera egen biografi har visat sig vara mycket viktigt för författares identitet. Om författarna inte få rosor från litteraturkritiker och ingen köper deras biografier så kan man ju alltid ge bort dem till barnbarnen.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (magisterexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 poäng / 15 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085983693</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Studia  Fennica Stockholmiensia</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Miten viranomaiset puhuttelevat kanslaisia tiedotteissaan - Ruotsin ja Suomen viranomaistekstien vertailua</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (masterexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">15 poäng / 22,5 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085995144</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">LÄRARUTBILDNINGEN</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Onko aika kehittää äidinkielen oppikirjoja? Kartoitus Ruotsin peruskoulun suomen opetuksessa käytetyistä oppikirjoista</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Is it Time to Develop School Books in the Mother Tongue? A survey of the books used in Finnish language teaching in Swedish primary schools</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;Päättötyöni on kvalitatiivinen kartoitus kymmenestä Ruotsin peruskoulussa vuosiluokilla 1&lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt;5 suomen kielen opetuksessa käytetystä oppikirjasta. Kartoitusten lisäksi olen haastatellut kolmea opettajaa ja saanut vastauksia kyselykaavakkeisiin 11 opettajalta heidän mielipiteistään oppikirjoista. Aihe, suomen kielen oppikirjojen kartoitus ja mielipidekysely kirjoista, on tarpeellinen &lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;sillä suomen kieli on ollut yksi Ruotsin viidestä virallisesta&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;kansallisesta vähemmistökielestä vuodesta 2000 ja peruskouluasetuksen mukaan kaikilla oppilailla on Ruotsin peruskouluissa oikeus oppia ja kehittää suomen kieltä, jos heillä on ennestään perustava kielitaito.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaikka suomi on ollut virallinen vähemmistökieli jo kymmenen vuotta ja koululainmuutos, jonka mukaan suomen kielen ei enää tarvitse olla aktiivinen kotikieli&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;on ollut voimassa kaksi vuotta, vasta tämän syksyn aikana painettiin ruotsinsuomalaisia varten ensimmäinen oppikirjasarja 20 vuoteen. 1970- ja 80-luvuilla teetettiin kolme kirjasarjaa, mutta sen jälkeen opettajat ovat joutuneet käyttämään Suomessa tuotettuja ja suomalaisia oloja varten suunniteltuja kirjoja, eivätkä kirjat tutkimukseni mukaan täytä kaikkia ruotsalaisen kurssisuunnitelman tavoitteita. Suomen kielen opettajat ovat kuitenkin tyytyväisiä oppikirjoihinsa, vaikka niissä on puutteita; niiden suurin heikkous on, että ne sisältävät ruotsinsuomalaisille liian vaikeita sanoja ja lauseita&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;Mitt examensarbete är en kvalitativ kartläggning med fokus på 10 skolböcker som idag används i finskundervisningen i den svenska grundskolan i årskurserna ett till fem. Som komplement till kartläggningen har tre lärare intervjuats och 11 lärare har besvarat ett frågeformulär med åsikter om de böcker som de använder. Uppsatsens ämne är relevant eftersom finskan sedan år 2000 är ett av Sveriges fem officiella, nationella minoritetsspråk. Enligt grundskoleförordningen har alla elever med grundläggande kunskaper i finska rätt att lära sig och att utveckla språket i skolan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finskan har varit ett officiellt minoritetsspråk i tio år och ändringen i skollagen, att finskan inte längre behöver vara ett aktivt hemspråk för att ge rätt till modersmålsundervisning, kom för två sedan. Ändå är det först nu i höst som de första skolböckerna på 20 år för sverigefinska elever tryckts. På 1970- och 80-talen trycktes tre bokserier, men sedan dess har lärarna fått förlita sig på böcker producerade i Finland som enligt min forskning inte uppfyller alla kursplanens kriterier. Modersmålslärarna är nöjda med sina böcker även om de har brister. Deras största svaghet är, att de innehåller för svåra ord och meningar för sverigefinska elever.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;My degree project is a qualitative survey of 10 books used in Swedish primary schools in Finnish teaching. As a complement to the survey I interviewed three teachers and handed out questionnaires to eleven more, asking for their opinions of the school books they are using. The subject is relevant, as Finnish has been one of the five official minority languages in Sweden since the year 2000. According to the Compulsory School Ordinance on the nine-year compulsory school all students with a basic knowledge of Finnish have the right to learn and develop the language in school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finnish has been a national minority language for ten years and two years ago a change in the school law was introduced, which entitles pupils to classes in Finnish even when Finnish is not an active language at their home. Nevertheless, it was only this autumn that, for the first time in 20 years, school books were printed for Finns in Sweden. In the 1970s and 1980s three book series were printed, but since then teachers have had to rely on books produced in Finland, which, according to the findings of my degree project, do not meet all the criteria of the Swedish course syllabus. The teachers of Finnish are satisfied with the books, although the books have weaknesses; the biggest weakness is that they have too advanced words and sentences for Swedish Finnish pupils.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (yrkesexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 poäng / 15 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/07712/B31D9AB9E2637D99967BB2B693997BA5BCD27097</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">9. toukokuuta - Eurooppa - päivä (2006)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085953112</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">”Uutisista hyvää iltaa.” Kielenhuollontutkielma SVT:n uutisjuttujen ymmärrettävyydestä</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aim with this essay is to specify and to describe such linguistic elements, which hamper readability of the Finnish news language at SVT: s Uutiset. The aim is also to give examples on how, with the aid of language cultivation, readability of the Finnish news language can be improved. Yet another aim is to write an essay that is useful in news reporters’ daily work and that the essay justifies and enthuses them to an active language cultivation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study is based on 224 news cases, done by SVT: s Finnish editorial staff between January 3 and July 1, 2005. The study method is qualitative and descriptive, and the study includes morphology, syntax and semantics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result of the study shows that the linguistic elements that hamper readability of news language are long sentences and long attribute chains, noun style, postpositional constructions, word order and cases, and statistical expressions. These linguistic elements influence how clearly, easily and concise news language is considered. Problematic seems also to be how sentences, constituents and words are to be emphasized and how they should be tied together in a cohesive and correct way. The linguistic elements that often occur in the material are common also in other text genres and are well-known within language cultivation literature.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (masterexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 poäng / 15 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085953115</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">”Kyllähän ne kysy että halutaanks me niinku” Huddingelaisnuorten puhekielen verbikongruenssi</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aim with this paper was to study and describe how the congruence in 1. P Sg, 1. P Pl and 3. P Pl (mä luen, me luetaan, ne lukee) appear in spoken Sweden Finnish among Sweden Finns teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study was based on a radio interview with 17 upper secondary school students from Huddinge, south of Stockholm. Some comparative data was also provided for in studies of congruence between spoken Sweden Finnish and Finnish in Finland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, a discussion about the influence of Swedish on the congruence in Sweden Finnish, and the difference in congruence between boys and girls were included. The study method was descriptive and quantitative, but also qualitative observations were made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result of the study implied that the congruence in 1. P Sg among the informants was around 99 %. The proportion of congruent forms appeared to the same extent among boys and girls. 0.5 % of all cases was constituted by incongruence in 1. P Sg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incongruence in 1. P Pl was 100 % among the informants. The incongruent form was the Passive "me luetaan" or "ø luetaan". The girls used the pronoun "me" 20 % more than the boys did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incongruence in 3. P Pl among the informants was about 99 %. The verb in 3. P Pl was in the form 3. P Sg "ne lukee" or "ø lukee". The incongruent forms appeared to the same extent among boys and girls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The differences in the congruence in spoken Sweden Finnish were small between the Sweden Finns and Finnish teenagers. The congruent form of standard Finnish in Sweden Finnish was used very seldom in either of the groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conclusions were that the Sweden Finns may deliberately want to avoid standard Finnish forms in spoken Finnish. An inadequate education in standard Finnish in Sweden may also influence spoken Sweden Finnish. Swedish is an analytical language, and could therefore influence Sweden Finnish in a way that it becomes more analytical than spoken Finnish in Finland.&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (magisterexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 poäng / 15 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200111/BibliographicResource_1000085954452</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Komparatiivinen analyysi tempusten käytöstä suomen ja ruotsin kielissä</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">&lt;p&gt;The study deals with the usage of tenses in Finnish and Swedish. The analysis focuses on the tenses of finite verb-forms and the aim is to compare differences in tense usage in order to notice where if at all the tense usage differs. The material used comprises one Finnish novel, one Swedish novel and their translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Finnish novel chosen is written by Arto Paasilinna and is called Aatami ja Eeva. The Swedish novel is called Ingen mans land and it is written by Jan Guillou. These novels were chosen because they are both contemporary and the texts were comparable with regard to how much narrative and dialogue they contain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One problem with generalizing is, that authors as well as translators all have their own idiolect; a variety of a language unique to an individual. A translator may also use a different tense as a stylistic device, for example to enliven the text or to add some drama into it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis was, that due to the semantic similarities between the two languages the tense usage is very similar in Finnish and Swedish. Clear differences were not expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The findings of the study verified my hypothesis. However, the study showed that Finnish past perfect was often translated as imperfect tense in the Swedish text and vice versa. The tenses concerned are a "temporal couple", both of them indicating "the past of the past". It might be due to this that it has been possible to change the tense in the translation without affecting the meaning of the sentence. My conclusion is, that in addition to this altering the tense was in many cases a stylistic choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keywords: tenses, tense usage, Finnish, Swedish, translation&lt;/p&gt;</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Självständigt arbete på avancerad nivå (masterexamen)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 poäng / 15 hp</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200143/BibliographicResource_2000069286851</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Finnische runen finnisch und deutsch</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">hrsg. von G. H. von Schröter, mit einer musikbeilage</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">First ed., Upsala, 1819</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Contains the book-plate of Gustav Woldemar, freiherr von Biedemann</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2022902/8C97F8B3139A39CABAD68618C5AB2BDCABD1B652</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Kokki-kirja, elikkä Neuwoja tarpeellisempein Joka-aikasien- ja Pito-ruokien Laitoksee ...</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2022902/C4357980A2F98EBDE5896E847CD355720E535179</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">H. F. Vocabularium latino-sveco-germanico-finnonicum, in vsum juventutis</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095226599</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Folia Uralica Debreceniensia 10.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">A Debreceni Egyetem Finnugor Nyelvtudományi Tanszékének kiadványai</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tartalom ◊ Keresztes, László: The History and Research Findings ◊ of Finno-Ugric Studies in Debrecen. The fifty years of the Finno-Ugric Department ◊ (1952-2002) ◊ Agyagási Klára: Módszertani megjegyzések egyes török ◊ eredetűnek tartott mordvinföldi víznevek pontosabb etimológiai minősítéséhez ◊ Armutlieva, Christina: A tárgy pronominalizációja és ◊ elhagyása a keleti lappban ◊ Balogh Anita: A műveltetés kifejezései a magyarban és ◊ a finnben ◊ Csúcs Sándor: A személyes névmások a permi nyelvekben ◊ és az őspermiben ◊ Dusnoki Gergely: Passzív képzők a norvéglappban ◊ Fábián Orsolya: A mordvin bibliafordítás terminológiájáról ◊ Fejes László: Egy degrammatikalizációs folyamat az udmurtban ◊ Keresztes László: A magyar nyelv eredetkérdései (eredmények ◊ és kihívások a finnugrisztikában) ◊ Kiss Antal: Az udmurt-magyar, magyar-udmurt műfordításról ◊ Mantila, Harri: Dialect Use and the Social Construction ◊ of Identity ◊ Maticsák Sándor: Névszói morféma-alternációk az erza-mordvinban ◊ Rédei Károly: Még egyszer isten szavunk eredetéről ◊ Sulkala, Helena: Itämerensuomalaiset vähemmistökielet ◊ kirjakieliksi ◊ Winkler, Eberhard: Az uráli nyelvek habeo-szerkezetének ◊ történetéhez ◊ Zaicz Gábor: "H. P. lektorálta". Etimológiai ◊ szótárak műhelytitkaiból, avagy: Hajdú Péter emlékezete ◊ Ismertetések ◊ Keresztes László: Finn őstörténeti kérdések ◊ (Ennen, muinoin. Miten menneisyyttämme tutkitaan) ◊ Dusnoki Gergely: A magyar nyelv eredetkérdései a tudománytörténész ◊ szemszögéből ◊ (Hegedűs József: Hiedelem és valóság) ◊ Zaicz Gábor: Az oroszországi finnugor népek múltjáról ◊ és jelenéről ◊ (Rein Taagepera: A finnugor népek az orosz államban) ◊ Lähde, Sanna: Ünnepi könyv Pentti Leino tiszteletére ◊ (Äidinkielen merkitykset) ◊ Maticsák Sándor: A finnországi bevándorlók névadási szokásai ◊ (Sukunimi? Etunimi? Maahanmuuttajien nimijärjestelmistä) ◊ Keresztes László: A svédországi finn és lapp helynevekről ◊ (Ulla Swedell: Finska och samiska ortnamn i Sverige) ◊ Balogh Anita: Finnországi szakszótárak ◊ Armutlieva, Christina: Többnyelvű politikai szótár ◊ (Hétnyelvű politikai és diplomáciai glosszárium) ◊ Kirli Ausmees: Új finn-észt nagyszótár ◊ (Soome-eesti suursonaraamat. Suomi-viro suursanakirja) ◊ Maticsák Sándor: Erza-mordvin értelmező szótár ◊ Fábián Orsolya: A mordvinok a nyelvész szemével - D. ◊ V. Cigankin összegyűjtött írásai, 75. születésnapja tiszteletére ◊ Kiss Antal: Útikönyv a vogulok és osztjákok földjéről ◊ Krónika ◊ Tanszéki beszámoló a 2002-2003. tanévről (Keresztes László) ◊ Utószó - Saatesanat - Järelsona - Afterword - Nachwort</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">A speciális karakterek megjelenítéséhez a TTF.ZIP file-ban levő TrueType betűkészletet is telepíteni kell a Windows-ban.</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095226200</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Ihmisen murhenäytelmä</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Az ember tragédiája</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">javított formátum</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095225834</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Az ország titka</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Marcus Mezentius Manilianus tizenegy levele a Kr. u. 30. esztendő tavaszáról</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Ország titka</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tartalom ◊ ELSŐ LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Mezentius Tulliának. ◊ MÁSODIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ HARMADIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Mezentius Manilianus Tulliának. ◊ NEGYEDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ ÖTÖDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ HATODIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus üdvözli Tulliát; valami olyat köszönt benne, mely már régen elmúlt. ◊ HETEDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ NYOLCADIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ KILENCEDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Tulliának. ◊ TIZEDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus ismét üdvözli Tulliát. ◊ TIZENEGYEDIK LEVÉL ◊ Marcus Mezentius Manilianus üdvözli Marcust, aki volt.</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Ismertető Az újtestamentumi tárgyú mű, amelynek főhőse Az emberiség ellenségei című, Nero korában játszódó regény (840705) főszereplőjének, Minutusnak az apja: Marcus Mezentius Manilianus, "római polgár". Ő is a jellegzetes, kiábrándult-kereső, értelmiségi módra világpolgár Waltari-hősök rokona. Szerelmi kalandjai miatt került Rómából Alexandriába, s most az ottani "édes élet" és könyvtári kutatások után félig-meddig véletlenül vetődik el Jeruzsálembe éppen azon a napon, amikor Jézust keresztre feszítik. Jóslatokban való jártassága és golgotai élményei nem hagyják nyugodni: nyomozni kezd "a világ királyának és országának titkai" után. Részese lesz a feltámadás titokzatos élményének és az ennek nyomán kialakuló bizonytalan, várakozással teli heteknek, amikor nemcsak körülötte, benne is változások zajlanak le. Ez esetben azonban nem ő az igazán fontos Waltari számára, hanem inkább az, hogy csodavárás, hit, hiszékenység és kételkedés válfajait és hullámzásait kövesse végig az egymás után megjelenő, jól ismert bibliai szereplők gondolkodásában és viselkedésében (Pontius Pilátus, Mária Magdaléna, cirénéi Simon, a tanítványok, Lázár, Mária és Márta stb.). A keretkonstrukció így nem lesz minden mesterkéltség nélkül való, az író fantáziája, atmoszférateremtő és beleélő képessége azonban ezt feledteti velünk. Különös tehetséggel képes érzékeltetni a földrajzi, történelmi és pszichikai összetevőknek azt a sajátos találkozását, amelynek következtében a valóság jelenségei, tényei a csoda formáját öltik magukra, s a csodák mint valóságos tények jelennek meg a világban és az emberek tudatában. A regény kormegidéző ereje és témája miatt - számíthat a többi Waltari-műhöz hasonló érdeklődésre. Forrás: Új Könyvek adatbázisa, 1994-2000 Szerk.: Könyvtári Intézet, 2002 http://www.ki.oszk.hu/szervezeti-gyio.html#uk</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">korrektúrázott szöveg</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/92006/BibliographicResource_1000095225530</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Hosszúéletű Harald</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Editio Plurilingua</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">2000/9.</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Harald Pitkäikäinen</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/9200354/BibliographicResource_3000058465926</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Vaitelias tanskalainen : kirja velvollisuutensa täyttäneistä</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Digitalisering 2012 af udgaven: Helsinki: G. W. Edlundin Kustannusosakeyhtiö, 1917 (184 s.)</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Efter Det Kongelige Biblioteks eksemplar: Verdenskrigen 1914-18 8° 0484</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/07722/97D3E456B9A22867DF6B5A8A297CC72DFB92FD3F</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Puhe televisiossa Suomen EU-kansanäänestyksen ratkettua (16. 10.1994)</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/09404/id_oai_rcin_org_pl_5663</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Antiquités du Nord finno-ougrien. 1, Âges de la pierre et du bronze</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">X, 94 s. : il. ; 35 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tekst równolegle w j. francuskim i fińskim</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Text parallel in French and Finnish</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">X, 94 p. : ill. ; 35 cm</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/09404/id_oai_rcin_org_pl_5667</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Antiquités du Nord finno-ougrien. 5, L'âge du fer : antiquités des Provinces Baltiques</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tekst równolegle w j. francuskim i fińskim</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">S. [6], 325-399 : il. ; 35 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Bibliografia</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Bibliography</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">P. [6], 325-399 : ill. ; 35 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Text parallel in French and Finnish</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/09404/id_oai_rcin_org_pl_4908</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Antiquités du Nord finno-ougrien. 3, L'âge du fer : antiquités Morduines, Mériennes et Tschoudes</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">S. [6], 179-242 : il. ; 35 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tekst równolegle w j. francuskim i fińskim</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Text parallel in French and Finnish</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">P. [6], 179-242 : ill. ; 35 cm</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/09404/id_oai_rcin_org_pl_28959</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Mordvalaisten pukuja ja kuoseja 1.-[6]</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">6 vol. ([2] s., 16 k. tabl. ; k. tabl. 155-199 ; 4. k. tabl. ; k. tabl. 5-10 ; k. tabl. 11-30 ; k. tabl. 31-45) : il. ; 31 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Objaśnienia il. równolegle w j. fińskim i niemieckim</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">6 vol. ([2] p., 16 leaves of plates ; leaves of plates 155-199 ; 4. leaves of plates ; leaves of plates 5-10 ; leaves of plates 11-30 ; kleaves of plates 31-45) : ill. ; 31 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Commentaries to ill. parallel in Finnish and German</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/09404/id_oai_rcin_org_pl_3015</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Sananen neolitisen kikikauden kuvanveisto-taiteesta</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Odb. z: Suomalais-Ugrilaisen Seuran Aikakauskirja = Journal de la Société Finno-Ougrienne; 23 (1906) 28</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Bibliogr. przy tekście</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 s. : il. ; 25 cm</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Reprint from: Suomalais-Ugrilaisen Seuran Aikakauskirja = Journal de la Société Finno-Ougrienne ; 23 (1906) 28</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Bibliographical footnotes</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">10 p. : ill. ; 25 cm</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_99165</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Aura, nr: 65</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Tietoja Turun kaupungista ja Länsi-Suomesta</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_99206</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Keski-Suomi, nr: 75</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_92932</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Uusi Suometar, nr: 140</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_94894</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Satakunta, nr: 31</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Sanomia Länsi-Suomesta</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_9519</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Waasan Lehti, nr: 55</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_94775</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Waasan Lehti, nr: 97</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_94873</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Satakunta, nr: 96</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Sanomia Länsi-Suomesta</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_94909</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Satakunta, nr: 20</field><field name="proxy_dc_description">Sanomia Länsi-Suomesta</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_89289</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Savo-Karjala, nr: 86</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_89321</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Rauman Lehti, nr: 38</field></doc><doc><field name="europeana_id">/2021010/oai_digi_kansalliskirjasto_fi_89558</field><field name="proxy_dc_title">Savo-Karjala, nr: 147</field></doc></add>